Joyce Wang 王心怡 | website: joycewang.me | email: joycexinyiwang@cmu.edu

PROFILE

software engineer, interdisciplinary researcher, theater maker

practiced in the fields of computer science, drama, art, and design experienced in collaborating with people of diverse cultural and academic backgrounds able to master new technologies quickly and work with complex data

EDUCATION

Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh, PA, 2015-2020

B.C.S.A in Computer Science and Drama (Video and Media Design)

GPA: 3.73/4.0 | Dean's List: fall 2015, spring 2016, spring 2017, fall 2017, spring 2018

Senior Honors Thesis: Evaluating Journalistic Practices on Twitter Using Social Network Analysis

WORK EXPERIENCE

Disney Research lab associate, summer 2018

- Designed new workflow for creatives and engineers to collaboratively author intelligent virtual characters
- Designed and prototyped tools that assist creative writers in the authoring process
- Submitted research paper "Conversational Approach to the Creative Authoring of Intelligent Virtual Characters" for ACM IUI Conference (March 2019)

Microsoft Explorer internship, summer 2017

- Designed and implemented web applications for online marketplace service
- Front-end and back-end code have been deployed

Human-Computer Interaction Institute, CMU research assistant, summer 2016

- Designed and Implemented survey applications for studies in mobile privacy

School of Computer Science, CMU teaching assistant for 15-112, fall 2016

- Led recitations, hosted review sessions, mentored students on term projects.

LEADERSHIP AND INITIATIVES

IMPAQT (Initiating Meaningful Pittsburgh and Qatar Ties), spring 2017-present

- facilitate communication and collaboration between Carnegie Mellon University's Qatar and Pittsburgh campuses
- went on spring break cultural exchange program in Doha, Qatar

CMU Listens co-director, fall 2017-present

- new student initiative dedicated to spreading awareness and competency around the importance of active listening within the Carnegie Mellon campus
- organized on-campus workshops and off-campus retreats

"Translations" creator/director/performer, fall 2017

- multimedia interactive theater piece about the story of a Chinese actor in New York
- opened as part of Carnegie Mellon School of Drama's student independent work festival

Interactive media design for "How to Put on a Sock" fall 2017

- theater performance about sex education policies in America today
- created a real-time text message interaction and data visualization system on stage

Independent research on the education of migrant children in mainland China 2014-2015

- conducted interviews and consulted literature in English and Chinese
- wrote 60-page research paper and gave TED Talk-style presentation to the Phillips Academy community
- funded and supported by the Community and Multicultural Development (CAMD) office at Phillips Academy

GRANTS AND AWARDS Fifth Year Scholarship (Carnegie Mellon University), 2019-2020

USITT-USA Prague Quadrennial 2019 Emerging Designer Exhibit, 2019

Small Undergraduate Research Grant (Carnegie Mellon University), 2017

CAMD Scholarship (Phillips Academy), 2014-2015

SKILLS

software engineering: c++, c#, python, java, javascript, web development, Android development; **art/design:** Unity, Processing/p5.js, Three.js, TouchDesigner, Max/MSP, Millumin, SketchUp, rapid prototyping, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Premiere; **languages:** Mandarin (native proficiency), French (preliminary proficiency)